Daas Hatweek

Dubai, United Arab Emirates | (+971) 54 215 6858 | hatweekdaas@gmail.com | Portfolio | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Favorably motivated Software Engineer with over **3** years of experience in software development, specializing in Django and Django Rest Framework for server-side logic and React JS for client-side. Proficient in foundational programming principles with a drive to craft high-performing web applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Self-Employed, Full Stack Developer

May 2021 - Present

Remote

- Spearheaded development for 6 projects, prioritizing robust backend solutions using Django and Django REST framework.
- Designed user interfaces for 3 web applications, leading to a 20% improvement in user engagement metrics.
- Managed 2 projects simultaneously, meeting 100% of deadlines and deliverables effectively.
- Implemented automated testing protocols, resulting in a 30% reduction in bug occurrences across all projects.

AL-Wadi Medical Center, Full Stack Developer

Dec. 2022 - Sept. 2023

Homs, Syria

- Led a team of **3** developers in developing a comprehensive platform digitizing medical operations.
- Developed a web application and a mobile application using MySQL, Django Rest Framework, Flutter, React, and Figma.
- Ensured 100% secure data handling and seamless integration between applications.
- Conducted thorough unit tests, resulting in a 95% test coverage across both applications.

W-BID, Junior Backend Developer

Feb.2021 - Dec.2021

Homs, Syria

- Contributed to a cross-functional team in the creation of a mobile app for online bidding, resulting in a 30% decrease in auction processing times.
- Developed API endpoints and structured database schema, resulting in a 25% reduction in server response time.
- Integrated Stripe payment method, leading to a 15% increase in successful transactions.
- Directed and facilitated active problem-solving discussions among the development team, resulting in the successful attainment of all project objectives; fostering a culture of teamwork and innovation to drive project success.

EDUCATION

Al-Baath University - Bachelor of Science

Homs, Syria

Informatics Engineering Department of Software Engineering and Information Systems

Nov. 2023

• Graduated in the top 10 of the class and achieved the highest score on the National Exam in the college

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript, C++

Back End Development: Django, Django Rest Framework, Flask

Front End Development: React JS, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Vue JS, MUI, Bootstrap

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Mongo DB

DevOps and Tools: Version Control Systems (Git), Azure, Docker, JIRA, Scrum, CI/CD pipelines

Architecture and Technologies: MVC, REST, Microservices, WebSocket, RabbitMQ

Additional Tools & Skills: Agile Methodologies, Figma (UI/UX design)

Machine Learning: Scikit-learn, PyTorch

Languages

- English Fluent
- · Arabic Native